Finding Aid for Gerald H. Hoag papers, 1918-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Gerald H. Hoag papers 1918-1978
Hoag, Gerald H.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize folder
85196 Aa 2; UAm
Ann Arbor (Mich.) theatre manager, later area manager of Butterfield Theatres, Inc. Personal correspondence, business memoranda, clippings, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Gerald H. Hoag (donor no. 6703 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Gerald H. Hoag was a motion picture theater manager in Ann Arbor, Michigan. He worked at both the Majestic and Michigan theatres. He later became area manager of Butterfield Theatres.
The Gerald H. Hoag collection relates to his career as a theatre manager in Ann Arbor and with the Butterfield Theatres Company. The collection includes correspondence, business communications, topical files relating to his activities in Ann Arbor, and photographs of theaters, celebrities, and advertising. Of interest are blueprints of the Michigan Theatre, booking ledger for the Majestic Theatre in the period of 1918-1921 and 1925-1926, and scattered box office reports.
Subjects:
Butterfield Michigan Theatres Company.; Hoag, Gerald H.; Majestic Theatre (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Michigan Theatre (Ann Arbor, Mich.).; Motion picture industry.; Theaters--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Theaters.; Arcade Theater (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Butterfield, W. V.; Celebrities.; Entertainment.; Hoag, Gerald H.; Interiors.; Liberty Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Lobbies.; Majestic Theatre (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Michigan Theatre (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Orchestras.; State Theatre (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Theaters--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Men's Glee Club.; Waring, Fred, 1900-1984.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence and business communications
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947-1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970-1972 and 1978 (Box 1)
- Topical files
  - Blueprints of Michigan Theatre (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about G. H. Hoag (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about Ann Arbor theatres (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and correspondence re. Ann Arbor premier of "It Happens Every Spring" (Box 1)
  - Speech notes, articles, etc. (Box 1)
  - Booking information (Orpheum Theatre, Ann Arbor) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous receipts and booking information, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Notebooks containing booking information for Majestic Theatre, 1918-1921 and 1925-1926, 2 volumes (Box 1)
- Photographs
  (see also oversize photographs)
  - Advertising (Box 1)
  - Butterfield, W.V. (Box 1)
  - Celebrities
    - A-B (Box 1)
    - C-D (Box 1)
    - F-K (Box 1)
    - L-P (Box 1)
    - R-T (Box 1)
    - W-Z (Box 1)
  - Celebrity visits (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Theater exteriors
    - Michigan Theatre (Box 1)
    - Other theaters (Box 1)
  - Theater interiors and personnel (Box 1)
  - University groups (Box 1)
  - Waring, Fred (Box 1)